Hula, Erich; Papers ger044
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence Files, 1927-1985; 2; 239 file folders
  - Schwab, George, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 188)
  - Schwarzenberger, G., 1937; 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 189)
  - Schwelb, Egon, 1947; 1955-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 190)
  - Seipel (Bundeskanzler), 1927 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 191)
  - Shuster, George N., 1945; 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 192)
  - Simmons, Ernest J., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 193)
  - Simons, Hans, 1941; 1955-1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 194)
  - Smend, R., 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 195)
  - Social Research, 1942; 1977; 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 196)
  - Speier, Hans, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 197)
  - Srubar, Ilja, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 198)
  - Stadelmayer, Peter, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 199)
  - Staehle, Hans, 1946; 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 200)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1950; 1961-1962; 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 201)
  - Steiner, Herbert, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 202)
  - Stern, Fritz, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 203)
  - Stoessinger, John G., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 204)
  - Stourzh, Gerald, 1964-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 205)
  - Strauss, Leo, 1943-1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 206)
  - Stuttgarter Zeitung (Robert Haerdter), 1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 207)
  - Swearingen, Victor C., 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 208)
  - Tenbruck, Friedrich, 1973-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 209)
  - Thompson, Kenneth W. (Rockefeller Foundation, University Press of America), 1957-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 210)
  - Thompson, Wayne C., 1971-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 211)
  - Timasheff, Nicholas S., 1953; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 212)
  - Unger, Frederich, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 213)
  - Universitas (H. Walter Bähr), 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 214)
  - The University of Chicago (C. Herman Pritchett), 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 215)
  - University of Colorado (Leo C. Riethmayer), 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 216)
  - University of Denver (Josef Korbel), 1960-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 217)
  - The University of Wisconsin, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 218)
  - Valle, Raymond, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 219)
  - Van Sickle, John V., 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 220)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur, 1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 221)
  - Virally, M., 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 222)
  - Voegelin, Erich, 1941-1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 223)
  - Volwiler, A. T., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 224)
  - von Fritz, Kurt, 1945-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 225)
  - Waber, Leopold, 1927 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 226)
  - Walsh, G. G. (Thought), 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 227)
  - Watkins, James T. IV, 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 228)
  - Welch, William, 1965; 1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 229)
  - Wertheimer, Egon, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 230)
  - White, Howard, 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 231)
  - Wild, Payton S., 1939 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 232)
  - Willcox, Walter F., 1956-1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 233)
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 234)
  - Wilson, Francis G., 1943-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 236)
  - Wolfers, Arnold, 1957-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 237)
  - Wyzanski, Charles E. Jr., 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 238)
  - Zernatto, Riccarda, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 239)
- Published and Unpublished Writings by Erich Hula, 1924-1984; 3; 288 file folders
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Writings in German, 1924-1938; 3.1; 55 file folders
    This sub-series contains publications and typescripts of articles in German on issues in labor, law, parliamentary reform and economics, written by Hula before his emigration to the United States.
    - "Von Monroe bis Coolidge". Periodical issue (Der oesterreichische Volkswirt), 1924 January 04 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 1)
    - "Juristenzeitung. Zur Rechtsprechung der Geschwornengerichte", 1924 January 23; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 2)
    - "Popper-Lynkens und das Problem der Strafe". Periodical issue (Gerichts-Zeitung), 1924 June (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 3)
    - "Zum neuen Parteiprogramm der österreichischen Sozialdemokratie", 1926; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 4)
    - "Gegen den Ständerat". Periodical issue (Der oesterreichische Volkswirt), 1926 September 25 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 5)
    - "Demokratie. Zur Diskussion des Soziologentages". Periodical issue (Der oesterreichische Volkswirt), 1926 October 30 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 6)
    - "Wandlungen im Wahlrechtsproblem. Listenwahlen und Freiheit", 1926 December 31; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 7)
    - Publications, 1927 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 8)
    - "Der Kampf gegen Proporz", 1927 January 01; Reprints (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 9)
    - "Die staatsrechtliche Durchführung des Anschlusses Oesterreichs an das Deutsche Reich. Eine neue Schrift Professor Kelsens", 1927 March 16; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 10)
    - "Alkoholfrage und Politik in Amerika. Die rechtlichen Probleme der Prohibition", 1929 August 14; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 11)
    - "Deutscher und englischer Parlamentarismus", 1932; Reprints (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 12)
    - "Die amerikanische Präsidentenwahl", 1932 June (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 13)
      Typescript of radio talk.
    - "Die Revision der Pariser Friedensverträge", 1932 November (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 14)
    - "Kriegsschulden und Reparationen", 1932 December (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 15)
    - "Ein Präzedenzfall des deutsch-österreichischen Zollunionpaktes. Das französisch-belgische Zollunionsprojekt von 1841", Undated; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 16)
    - "Der amerikanische Senat. Sein Einfluss auf die innere und äussere Politik der Vereinigten Staaten", Undated; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 17)
    - "Wahlreform?", Undated; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 18)
    - "Ständische Verfassungsreform". Periodical issue (Mitteilungen des Verbandes österreichischer Banken und Bankiers), 1933 December (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 19)
    - Arbeiterkammer leaflets (2), authored by Hula, 1934 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 20)
    - "Die autoritären Elemente in der neuen österreichischen Verfassung". Periodical issue (Mitteilungen des Verbandes österreichischer Banken und Bankiers), 1934 July (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 21)
    - "Georges Sorel", 1934 July 01; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 22)
    - "Georges Sorel und die Arbeiterbewegung", 1934 July 08; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 23)
    - "Roosevelts Wiederaufbaugesetzgebung und der Oberste Gerichtshof". Co-authored by J. A. C. Grant. Periodical issue (Oesterreichische Anwalts-Zeitung), 1934 October 20 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 24)
    - "Berufsständische Ordnung und Gewerkschaft", 1934 December 04; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 25)
    - "Der faschistische Korporativstaat", 1935 March 27; Typescript and offprint (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 26)
    - "Arbeitsstreitigkeiten", 1935 March 27 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 27)
      typescript of lecture.
    - "Die korporative Organisation", 1935 September 27 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 28)
    - "Arbeiter- und Angestelltenfragen. Der Februar wird liquidiert", 1935 May 05; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 29)
    - "Roosevelt und seine Richter", 1935 June 08; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 30)
    - "Arbeiter- und Angestelltenfragen. Die Genfer Arbeitskonferenz", 1935 July 07; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 31)
    - "Das Verfahren in Genf", 1935 September 24; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 32)
    - "Das englische Kabinettsystem in nationalsozialistischer Beleuchtung", 1935 October 20; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 33)
    - "England - ein parlamentarischer Staat?" Periodical issue (Der oesterreichische Volkswirt), 1935 November 02 (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 34)
    - "Gesamtarbeitsverträge", 1936; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 35)
    - "Charles Mauras und die Aktion Française", 1936 January 04; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 36)
    - "Grundfragen der Schlichtung", 1936 February 12; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 37)
    - "Völkerbundesreform", 1936 June 20; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 38)
    - "Die Genfer Arbeitskonferenz", 1936 July 01; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 39)
    - "Jugend in Not-Staat in Not", 1936 September 06; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 40)
    - "Die Verfassung gewinnt Leben", 1936 September 15; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 41)
    - "Spanien und Europa im Blickfeld eines politischen Sehers". Periodical issue (Monatsschrift für Kultur und Politik), 1936 November (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 42)
    - "Der Sieg der Tradition", 1936 December 13; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 43)
    - "Berufständische Schlichtung im Gewerbe", 1937 April 10; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 44)
    - "Die berufständischen Ausschüsse", 1937 June 04; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 45)
    - "Neue Handelskommen", 1937 June 09; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 46)
    - "Das neue Handelskammerngesetz I, II", 1937 July 07; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 47)
    - "Die Tätigkeit der steierischen Arbeiterkammer im Vorjahr", 1937 July 21; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 48)
    - "Konsumentenschutz", 1937 August 14; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 49)
    - "Berufsständische Selbstverwaltung", 1937 December 18; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 50)
    - "Die freien Berufe in der berufsständischen Ordnung", 1937 December 19; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 51)
    - "Die berufständische Organisation der freien Berufe", 1938 January; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 52)
    - "Das Wirtschaftsjahr 1938", 1938 February; Clipping (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 53)
    - Untitled lecture, 1938 April 07; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 54)
    - "Rechtsstaat", ca. 1938; Typescript (Box 3 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 55)
  - Writings, primarily in English; reviews, 1939-1984; 3.2; 204 file folders
    This sub-series contains articles primarily in English from Hula's years in the United States. The series also contains reviews written by Hula, in German and in English, 1924-1984.
    - "Rise and Decline of European Socialism", 1939; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 1)
    - "The Corporative Experiment in Austria". Proofs, photocopy, 1939 February (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 2)
    - "Constitutional and Administrative Readjustments", 1939 May; Proofs, reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 3)
    - "The European Neutrals", 1940 May; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 3a)
    - "Control of the Conquered", 1941 May; Proofs, reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 4)
    - "Justice and Power". Periodical issue (The Voice of Austria), 1941 June (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 5)
    - "Empire or Commonwealth?" Periodical issue (The Voice of Austria), 1941 July (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 6)
    - "Limits of National Self-Determination". Periodical issue (The Voice of Austria), 1941 September (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 7)
    - "Nation and State". Periodical issue (The Voice of Austria), 1941 October (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 8)
    - "The Chimera of the National State". Periodical issue (The Voice of Austria), 1941 November (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 9)
    - "Pan Americanism: Its Utopian and Realistic Elements". Book chapter, 1942 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 10)
    - "Problems of Federal Organization", ca. 1942; Typescript (carbon) (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 11)
    - "Manifesto on the War". Periodical issue (The Commonweal), special issue, 1942 August 21 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 12)
    - "A General European Union: Critical Survey of Contemporary Projects", 1942 September; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 13)
    - "National Self-Determination Reconsidered", 1943 February; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 14)
    - "Problems of International Organization", 1943 September; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 15)
    - "Exchange of Populations. Reader Doubts Value as Remedy for Excessive Nationalism", 1944 February 16; Clipping (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 16)
    - "The Nationalities Policy of the Soviet Union", 1944 May; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 17)
      Also revised version for a paper 1951.
    - "The Dumbarton Oaks Proposals", 1945 May; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 18)
    - "Punishment for War Crimes", 1946 March; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 18a)
    - "The Revival of the Idea of Punitive War", 1946 September; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 19)
    - "Views on Nuremberg". Co-authored with Hans Morgenthau, Moorhouse F.X. Millar. Periodical issues (America), 1946 December 07 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 20)
    - Talks given at the New School for Social Research, 1948-1950; Typescripts (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 21)
    - de los Rios funeral speech, 1949; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 22)
    - "Sir Bernard Pares", 1949 May 09; Clipping (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 23)
    - "Four Years of the United Nations", 1949 December; Clipping (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 24)
    - Alvin Johnson tribute, 1949 December 18; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 25)
    - "Uniting for Peace Resolution". Mimeo, 1950 November 03 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 26)
    - "Karl Renner: His Life and His Work", 1951 January 18; Typescript, mimeo (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 27)
    - "On the Law of the United Nations", 1951; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 27a)
    - "Laws of War", 1952; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 28)
    - "The Living and the Written Charter of the United Nations". Grant application, 1954 February 08; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 29)
    - "Revision of the United Nations Charter. A Research Project I-XX", 1954-1955; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 30)
    - "Revision of the United Nations Charter. A Research Project XXI-XXXVI", 1954-1955; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 31)
    - "Arnold Brecht's Contribution to Comparative Government and International Relations", 1954 Spring; Clipping (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 32)
    - "The Bricker Amendment", ca. 1954; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 33)
    - "Boris Mirkine-Guetzévitch, 1892-1955", 1955 Fall; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 34)
    - "Studies in the Law and Politics of the United Nations", 1955 November; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 35)
    - Canadian lectures, 1955; Typescripts (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 36)
    - "The Korean War. A Case Study in Collective Security". Introduction, chapters 1-4, ca. 1956; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 37-39)
      Unpublished.
    - "Fundamentals of Collective Security". Proofs, reprints, 1957 Spring (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 40)
    - "A Design for a charter of the G.I.O", Undated; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 41)
    - "Comments on Problem IX: The Dumbarton Oaks Proposals: Economic and Social Cooperation", Undated; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 42)
    - "The Question of Russian Objectives", 1958; Typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 43)
      Published version.
    - "The Practical Uses of Theory" (with Hans Jonas, Solomon E. Asch, Adolph Lowe), 1959 Summer; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 44)
    - "United Nations", 1960; Clippings (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 45)
    - "The United Nations in Crisis", 1960 Winter; Proofs, reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 46)
    - German version: "Krise in den Vereinten Nationen", 1961 May; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 47)
    - Spanish version: "Las Naciones Unidas en crisis: dos versiones. II", 1961 July-1961 September; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 48)
    - "Weltregiment, Universalität und Machtpolitik", 1960 April 21; Clipping (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 49)
    - "Fünfzehn Jahre Vereinte Nationen", 1960 October; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 50)
    - "Hans Simons", 1961 May 29; Reprint (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 51)
    - "The United Nations in the Congo", 1962; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 52)
    - "Weltregiment und Weltpolitik im 20. Jahrhundert", 1963; Reprints (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 53)
    - Untitled typescript [Arnold Brecht's 80th birthday January 26, 1964], Undated (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 54)
    - "The United States and the United Nations", 1966; Reprints (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 1)
    - "Recht und Politik in den Vereinten Nationen", 1966; Reprints (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 2)
    - "In memoriam: Otto Kirchheimer, 1905-1965", 1966 Spring; Reprints (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 3)
    - "Guido Zernatto", 1968 February 01; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 4)
    - "Weltregiment und Weltpolitik heute", 1968 August; Reprints (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 5)
    - "Austrian Legal and Political Thought in the United States", 1968 December 05; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 6)
    - "Otto Kirchheimer. An Introduction to His Life and Work" (written with John H. Herz), 1969; Reprints (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 7)
    - "Problems of Minorities". Outline, 1971; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 8)
    - "Should the Promotion of Democracy be the Primary Purpose of American Foreign Policy?", 1971; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 9)
    - "Sovereignty Under Attack", 1971; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 10)
    - "A General European Union: Critical Survey of Contemporary Projects", 1971; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 11)
    - "Leo Strauss", 1974 October 18; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 12)
    - "Howard White 1912-1974", 1975 April 11; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 13)
    - "Arnold Brecht 1884-1977", 1977 Winter; Reprint, typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 14)
    - "Ein Grusswort aus New York" [Ossip Flechtheim], 1978; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 15)
    - "Fifty Years of International Government. Reflexions on the League of Nations and the United Nations", 1978; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 16)
    - "The United Nations". Introduction, notes to unpublished study, 1978 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 17)
    - "The United Nations". Part One, 1978; Typescripts (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 18-19)
    - "The Third United Nations", 1978 January 31; Typescript (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 20)
    - "Current Trends in International Law. A Critical Re-examination in Legal, Political and Sociological Terms". Outline, 1983 May 30 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 21)
    - Nationalism and Internationalism: European and American Perspectives, 1984; 3.2.76 (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings by ), Folder 22-28)
      - Introduction, notes, Typescripts (Box 5 (3.2.76-Nationalism and Internationalism: European and Ame), Folder 22)
      - Preliminary pages. Proofs, copies (Box 5 (3.2.76-Nationalism and Internationalism: European and Ame), Folder 23)
      - Published book, 1984 (Box 5 (3.2.76-Nationalism and Internationalism: European and Ame), Folder 24)
      - Photocopy of book (Box 5 (3.2.76-Nationalism and Internationalism: European and Ame), Folder 25)
      - Fordham University Press (H. George Fletcher). Correspondence concerning reprinting of texts (Box 5 (3.2.76-Nationalism and Internationalism: European and Ame), Folder 26)